Complete binary tree, a complete binary tree is a binary tree in which all the levels are completely
filled except possibly the lowest one, which is fold from the left a complete binary tree just like
a binary tree, but with two major differences all the leaf elements must lean towards the left.
This is very important, and the last leaf element might not have a right sibling.
Example a complete binary tree does not have to be a full binary tree.
Let's see the code and how to implement this complete binary tree.
We start by creating the note that contains the key and the reference to the left and the right, as
we have created this before in the previous videos and we have talked about the tree, the structure
of the note inside the tree and note creation when we initialize the note with that with the key or
the data inside it, with the past through meter inside, then you know the function and we initialize
the right and the left of any note to then not.
Now, let's count the number of nodes counting the number of nodes by passing the route.
We start by looping a fruit equal equal to now their returns zero and we return recursively the account
number.
So increase to the left and to the right.
We by using the sub tree.
So one is for the root count NUM nodes, the best route left.
So we start by passing the route left node.
We calculate and count all the elements, all the nodes to the left.
And then we start by using also recursive count NUM nodes and we pass through to the right.
And then we start counting all the nodes to the right.
So both left notes and right nodes plus one the route will give us the count number of the notes.
Why this is very important, we will because we are going to use it later on and check complete.
So.
Check complete.
This is a returning a bullion data type, and this function that took into the parameters that allowed
the index and the number of notes we start checking, as we have seen in the perfect binary tree.
And in the full binary tree, we need to make a method that took into the parameters the three things
or three very important things like in the perfect binary tree, the depth and the level.
But here we need to look in the index and the number of notes.
So if the tree is complete root equal, equal to null, then return true.
OK.
Why?
Because the root is equal, equal to no.
Then we don't have the empty tree is equal returning to check complete if index greater than the number
of nodes, then return false.
Why a complete binary tree is just like a full binary tree, but with two major differences all the
leaf must lean towards the left, and the last leaf element might not have a right sibling.
OK, no.
How to complete Binary Tree is created like select first element of the last of the list to be the root
node and then put the second element as the left chil- a child of the root node and the third element
had the right child.
We will keep repeating until you reach the last that this will be translated into making like a check
complete method that will recursively do this work if any of these Boolean expressions will return with
it to the Boolean expressions.
If a check complete, this is the first Boolean expression and this is the second Boolean expression
you see guys the and operate there between them.
If this is returning true and this is the returning true, that this function will return true and tell
us that this no, this three is a complete binary tree.
If any of them returns false or both of them returns false, then check complete method to return false.
And this is very important because we are going to check exactly if this is a complete or not, and
these conditions are very strict.
OK.
So we create in the main struct node.
It we create one, two, three, four, five and six.
Let me throw it.
If it is exactly maybe it's equal to this, so let's create one.
This is the route to the left.
This tool to the right is three.
We create left left.
Four left right.
Five.
Yes and right.
Left is equal to six.
You see, guys, this is leaning that the elements towards the left.
If I make right, then if I make a note only to the right here is six and leaning to that I would not
be a complete binary.
Three.
OK.
If we're on this program, we will see one of two possibilities either the three is a complete binary
tree.
If the check completed, we passed that we would then know that we have created here that index equal
to zero and then not count that it is returning from that count.
Note that we have create this method that we have created.
OK.
It will calculate the nodes.
It will pass the index and the route, and we check if it is a complete binary or not.
I want from you to put all this quotes to practice these codes and play with these codes.
And I want from you to paste the solution of this row, the output of this program.
So what does this program gives you?
A complete or not, a complete binary tree, I'm waiting your comments.
I'm with you, your suggestions, your answers, your recommendations.
And I hope your date as five stars on Udemy course to.